548 Buckeye Court Milton, ON L9E 1M2 Email: sana.adil.ak@gmail.com Cell: 905-926-6919 LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/sanaadil

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

 Motivated Electrical Engineer in Training with experience in creating and formatting panel layout transmittals for a 240/25 kV substation relay room. Primarily focused on understanding power and control system design. Excellent interpersonal and communication abilities acquired through writing, teaching and coaching experience. Proven willingness to take on any task to help the team succeed.

EDUCATION

 Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering University of Alberta, Edmonton AB 2012-2016

WORK EXPERIENCE

• Contract Podcast Script Writer

December 2020- Present

Xenda Education International Inc.

- Independently analyze and assemble a myriad expressions for each podcast episode in an album to be recorded
- Compose engaging and rich scripts for online English podcast courses that specializes in drilling and diversifying English expressions and idioms commonly used in Western daily life.
- Edit content and ensure accuracy and fact-check all content while ensuring timely delivery of albums.

• Academic Coach

January 2020- Present

StudySpot Educational Services

- Help and motivate students to do better in school by providing Academic and Executive Function skills needed to achieve set academic goals.
- Assist students in learning to plan and prioritize tasks in order to complete assignments and projects efficiently in a timely manner.
- o Guide students through problem solving strategies for various subjects in a measured manner
- Create customized lesson plans and schedules for individuals based on their learning preferences.
- Verbally and textually communicate session content and student progress to both students and parents on a regular basis using electronic resources such as email and spreadsheets.
- Support students with learning disabilities by using various learning strategies to coach and teach while regularly checking for student understanding

• Contract Electrical Engineer in Training: Substation Design

October 2018- January 2019

Citra Industries Inc.

- Created and formatted panel layout transmittals for a 240/25 kV substation relay room
- Designed and drafted, in Microstation V8i, AC, DC, component and terminal block wiring diagrams for Revenue Metering, Underfrequency Protection, Line Protection, Breaker Fail Protection, and Transformer Protection panel layouts

Production Operator

February 2017- October 2018

Salumatics Inc.

- o Prepared medical documentation for conversion to digital format
- Index and maintain ongoing medical accounts for clients
- Perform other clerical tasks in the conversion facility
- Ensure production quality and health and safety standards are met

548 Buckeye Court Milton, ON L9E 1M2 Email: sana.adil.ak@gmail.com Cell: 905-926-6919 LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/sanaadil

WordPress Developer

July 2016- Dec 2016

Aluminum and Plastic Cutting

- Assist in the building of client website using WordPress
- Assist in website traffic monitoring and optimization
- Modify existing PHP, CSS, and HTML code as needed
- Develop themes and plugins for client website use

Academic Tutoring Grades 1-12

2012-2016

- Facilitated independent student learning by introducing diverse teaching methods that took complex concepts in Math, English, History, Biology, and Chemistry and explaining concepts in easily understandable terms
- Prepared customized lesson plans, complete with explanations and examples, for each student prior to tutoring session
- Effectively identified, communicated, and addressed both strengths and weaknesses within the student's knowledge base to both the student and parent

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Final Design Project: Data Driven Haptic Simulator for Prostate Brachytherapy Surgery

- Assisted in the development of a real- time haptic simulation environment that can be used in prostate brachytherapy research
- Collected and assisted in the compilation and analyzation of data from various tissue samples for database creation in SQLite
- Programmed the statistical analysis component of simulator using C++ and SQLite in Windows Visual Studio environment
- Assisted in the programming of data collection from Haptic device using C++
- Evaluated statistical model performance against real and simulated data
- Created and completed troubleshooting on multiple test cases
- Worked collaboratively with client to research and determine suitable project goals and analysis techniques for lab data
- Organized project meetings with client and accurately estimated project budgets
- Met deadlines and budgets
- Created technical documentations and specifications

TECHNICAL AND COMPUTER SKILLS

- Microstation V8i
- Ivara
- Microsoft software suite and Microsoft Office
- C and C++ programming in Windows Visual Studio and the Eclipse development environment
- PowerWorld Simulator
- SQLite in Windows Visual Studio environment
- MATLAB
- PHP, CSS, and HTML
- Solidworks
- Photoshop and Inkscape

References available upon request.